

#### **BASIC INFORMATION**

#### ANDRES FELIPE ARBELAEZ RIOS

Birth Day: May 07/1989 Nationality: Colombia

ID number: 1'112.767.040 Colombia

South Av # 30-194 (+57) 301-601-5160 afar182@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Software Engineer with emphasis on Quality and Test Automation development. BS degree on computer science and music passionate with experience developing test automation scripts with Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, Appium, Jbehave and Cucumber, also experience developing using .NET Framework. I am a proactive individual with excellent skills for communication and teamwork, I like to propose and develop solutions to any kind of problems. Productive in both team-based and self-managed projects.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSIDAD TECNOLÓGICA DE PEREIRA

• BS System Engineer (Average 4.1/5) 2007 - 2012

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Aclara August 2018 - Today

-Software Engineer in Test, working remotely for Aclara Company based in ST Louis, MO, developing automated test cases for TWACS system, to control their services migrated from Windows services to an web page. I have been using BDD to elaborate the test cases, coding in Cucumber with Ruby and Watir.

#### Mastercard May 2017 - Today

-Software Engineer in Test working remotely for MasterCard company based in the US developing automated test cases for MasterPass payment method, covering the good functionality of the payment method in different merchant, test cases are developed to run in Native apps, mobile web versions of the merchants and web desktop versions of the merchants, I have used TestNG and Jbehave as the test engine depending on the approach of the test cases (BDD - TDD) using java and Selenium WebDriver.

# Globant Since January 2015 - May 2017 Test Automation Engineer Autodesk Inc.

-Software Engineer in Test for Autodesk Inc. Developing UI Automated Test cases for the Autodesk Knowledge Network system with Selenium Webdriver and TestNG on Java for web applications, and RestAssure to cover API testing for some endpoints.

## Globant January 2014 - January 2015 Test Automation Engineer The Climate Corporation.

-Software Engineer in Test for The Climate Corporation designing and running Test cases, developing UI Automated Test Scripts with BDD Cucumber tool, Ruby, Capybara, RSpec, Automated API testing with BDD using RestClient, cucumber, Ruby and Mimic to run fake endpoints.

## Projects:

- Agent Portal.
- MP Insurance.
- Agent Claims.

- Document generation

# INDRA COMPANY October 2012 - September 2013 Back-End Developer BBVA Spain Team Pereira, Colombia

- BackEnd developer for BBVA Bank
- Assigned to control QA of team developments
- Experienced with COBOL language

### INDRA COMPANY June 2012 - September 2012 . NET Developer Ecopetrol team Pereira, Colombia

- Collaborated in preparation of the team for Ecopetrol Bussines Rules
- Developed special educational projects.
- Developed some Ecopetrol's project manager software modules

#### **FREELANCE PROJECTS**

#### InAllMedia

## Software Engineer in test (July 2018 - Today)

-Working part time with a customer on developing Cucumber test cases for their site using Ruby as our development language.

## **UTest Community**

#### **Quality Insurance**

- Working as a Freelancer in this community since July of 2014.
- Bronze level with 81% of rating on Functional Testing
- Have participated in 47 cycles of 39 products and found 41 issues.

## KIWE-CORP May 2012 - July 2012

## .NET Developer

- Worked with a team of developers to implement RFID report generator software.
- Implemented software development on Windows Azure.
- Interacted with the team to brainstorm and implemented solutions for software reports

## UNIVERSIDAD TECNOLÓGICA DE PEREIRA (UTP) August 2010 – June 2012

# Web Developer and Designer Pereira, Colombia

- Developed principal web site for System Engineering program of Universidad Tecnológica de Pereira.
- Developed and Supported UTP's institutional web sites.

## **SKILLS**

Selenium WebDriver
Java
RSpec
TestNG
DDT
Ruby
BDD

- Cucumber- Appium- API Test Automation

- Capybara - JSON

- C# .NET
- COBOL
- Web Development
- ASP.NET
- PHP
- JavaScript

- SQLServer
- DevExpress
- XML
- -Jbehave
- -Api Testing

## **PREPARATION**

5 stars Developer student - Microsoft Virtual Academy

.Net Development – Microsoft Virtual Academy

English Language – Instituto de Lenguas Extranjeras Universidad Tecnológica de Pereira

Certification 160895 SENA virtual Diseño de Bases de datos con SQL

Certification 161721 SENA virtual Diseño Web con HTML y JavaScript.

Certification 224839 SENA virtual Programación en C++ (Nivel 1)

MVA's Active Student, Silverlight, Windows Phone 7, Windows Azure, WebMatrix.

Cisco (CCNA Student).

#### **PROJECTS AND INNOVATIONS**

## "¿Qué pasó aquí?" (2013)

Prototype of Social Network for geolocation of areas of interest using QR codes. Colombia's Startup Weekend Finalist and regional winner.

#### "Artemis" (2012)

Windows Phone / Windows 8 APP to help women who are pregnant to keep track of your pregnancy by constant data collection that would allow medical personnel to know the full picture. In case of emergency the application is responsible to contact with her family or doctor. This application have passed to the second round of the 2012 Microsoft Imagine Cup. (http://www.latarde.com/historico/56965-podrian-monitorear-un-embarazo-por-computador)

## Tupatupa (2011)

Bands and alternative culture Social Network Prototype oriented to dissemination and promotion of local events.

## ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND ACTIVITIES

- Imagine Cup 2012 Windows Phone Second Round competitor
- StartUp Weekend Colombia 2012 Finalist and Regional Winner.
- Microsoft STC Challenge 2011 Winner.
- Winner for three consecutive months in BBVA-Indra Internal challenge where thanks to my good quality and productivity developing put me at the top three positions of all team.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (native)

English (Advanced)

# **MORE INFORMATION**

B2 VISA for United States of America

**Andres Felipe Arbelaez Rios**